Partial Guide to the I. Edward Kiev Papers, circa 1860 - circa 1980 K0001
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Pamphlets, circa 1860-circa 1970; K0001 Series 4; 18 linear feet (Box 14, Box 11, Box 16, Box 15, Box 10, Box 51, Box 9, Box 8, Box 7, Box 18, Box 45, Box 46, Box 49, Box 2, Box 1, Box 53, Box 52, Box 48, Box 6, Box 17, Box 5, Box 4, Box 3)
  - Blut-Mrz 1933 (Box 45, Folder 1672)
  - Deutschen Juden als Soldaten im Kriege 1914-1918: eine statistische Studie, 1922 (Box 45, Folder 1673)
  - What's in the world?, 03/27/1958 (Box 45, Folder 1674)
    A report delivered on March 27, 1958 under the joint sponsorship of the Women's Auxilary and the Men's Club [Congregation Emanu-El]
  - Jdische Ehescheidung und der jdische Scheidebrief: eine historische Untersuchung, 1911 (Box 45, Folder 1675)
    Landes-Rabbinerschule in Budapest fr das Schuljahr, 1910-1911, 1911-1912, V. 34, 35-Jahresbericht (annual report)
  - Kaddish: man's reply to the problem of evil, 1962 (Box 45, Folder 1676)
    Studies in Torah Judaism, 4
  - Medical-ethical issues and the Jewish tradition, 1981 (Box 45, Folder 1677)
    The Backman lecture
  - Masekhet Derekh erets zuta: m kitsur perush veha-atikat vri-daytsh leman yavino khe-katan khe-gadol t divre hahamenu, z.l., 1878 (Box 45, Folder 1678)
    Library copy imperfect; missing final pages.
  - If eventually---why not now? = Oyb nisht yetst, ven?, 1936 (Box 45, Folder 1679)
  - Agadat Amora Erets-Yisral: kerekh 2, hel. 2, 1924 (Box 45, Folder 1680)
    Translation of "Die Agada der Palstinensischen Amorar." Library copy imperfect, missing final pages.
  - Haggadot Scrapbook, undated (Box 46, Folder 1599)
    Articles and book announcements related to the Haggadah prayer book. The materials are primarily bound booklet/pamphlets.
  - Idisher folks-ornament: ershte heft, 1920 (Box 48, Folder 1681)
    Russian title: Evreski narodny ornament
  - Omanuth: Quarterly bulletin of the Jewish National Museum Bezelel, Vol. 2, no. 2-3, 10/1941 (Box 48, Folder 1682)
    Supplement to Vol. 1, no 2-3. Published by the Society of Friends of the Museum
  - Pirsume Muzon ha-lohamim veha-partizanim, 1970 (Box 48, Folder 1683)
    Publications of the Museum of the Combatants and Partisans
  - Ka-tson la-tevah?, 1961 (Box 48, Folder 1684)
  - mdat Yisral be-sikhsukh Yisral-rav, 1967 (Box 48, Folder 1685)
    Title on t.p. verso: Israel's viewpoint in its conflict with the Arabs
  - Shir ha-shirim: Yidish fun Yehoash, 1932 (Box 48, Folder 1686)
  - Sefer Kinat sifre kodesh: ve-hu bikoret nemenah l tirgum ha-Rusi le-Sefer Tehilim asher tirgem ha-hakham Yehudah Leyb Mandelshtam ..., 1872 (Box 48, Folder 1687)
    Title also in Russian
  - Kuntres ha-Masoret: ha-meyuhas le-Ben-Asher; ve-nilvu elav eizeh hatakot mi-perush Sefer Yetsirah le-R' Yakov ben Nissim; m hakdamh, herot ve-tsiyunim mimeni Leib Dukes..., 1846 (Box 48, Folder 1688)
    In German: Kontres Hamassoreth. Includes translations from Perush sefer yetsirah attributed to R. Yaakov ben Nissim.
  - Sefer Agudat agadot, 1889 (Box 48, Folder 1689)
    Contents: 1. Ekton demer Yaakov -- 2. Eleh ha-masot -- 3. Mevaseret Tsiyon
  - Melitsah le-Furim: a. d. melitsat ha-piyut le-harbot bah simhat Purim u-mishteh ha-shikorim, 1700 - 1799 (Box 48, Folder 1690)
  - Din ve-heshbon: Kinus le-bayot ha-dat, 1942 (Box 48, Folder 1691)
  - West London Synagogue: book of devotions for use at the Beth Hayim, 1923 (Box 48, Folder 1692)
  - Urshprung fun gloybn, 1950 (Box 48, Folder 1693)
    Bibliotek frayer gedank; 1
  - Yedi'at 'amenu: demografyah ve-sotsyologyah, sefer limud ve-yun, 1923 (Box 48, Folder 1694)
    Bibliography included on p. 155-165, in Hebrew and German
  - My spiritual autobiography, 1953 (Box 48, Folder 1695)
    Reprinted from Thirteen Americans
  - Grace and blessings for various occasions, 1900 - 1938 (Box 48, Folder 1696)
    Hebrew and English
  - Abridged prayer book for Jews in the armed forces of the United States prepared and reiussed for the Jewish Welfare Board by the Jewish Publication Society of America, 1938 (Box 48, Folder 1697)
    Hebrew and English on opposite pages
  - Prayers: (Mourners' prayers), 1920 (Box 48, Folder 1698)
  - Book of Jonah: a paraphrase, 1962 (Box 48, Folder 1699)
  - Study as a mode of worship, 1925 (Box 48, Folder 1700)
    The Jewish library, v.3
  - Homer be-yad ha- yozer: Beur pizmon "Ki hinneh ka- homer" al pi kawwana gnuza meet... Shelomoh Pappenheim..., 1868 (Box 48, Folder 1701)
    Commentary on the literurgical hymn:" Like clay in the hand of the potter."
  - Reshimat kol sifre Yisral ahser nidpesu be-merika bi-sefat ver ... uve-sofah shete kinot l ... Hida, 1904 (Box 48, Folder 1702)
    Deinard, Ephraim, 1846-1930. Kearny: [s.n.] 664, 1904.
  - Dos Vort" bibliotek: no. 3 Mar. 1934, 3/1934 (Box 48, Folder 1703)
  - Konstitutsyon fun di yunayted garment vorkers of Amerika, 1910 (Box 48, Folder 1704)
  - Vi zikh tsu farhiten fun tuberkulozis und vi tsu heilen oystsehrung (shvindzukht), 1904 (Box 48, Folder 1705)
  - Sefer bohen tsadik, bo muva det shonot l odot ha-sefer megaleh temirin. Gam yesupar bo me-m u-medinat Kuzar, umi-bene menu vde adamah ba-hatsi ha-i Krim, 1963 (Box 48, Folder 1706)
    Reprint. Original published: Prague: Landau, 1838
  - Mahazeh mul mahazeh: kolel be-kirbo mi-sefer Di Shilderung: yeme pur yalduti ha-shakul bad be-vad et tahalukhot yamenu poh be-rvot ha-hayim = Machze mul machzeh, 1861 (Box 48, Folder 1707)
    Bookplate on verso of cover: Library of Samuel Mendelsohn, Wilmington North Carolina ... Presented in his memory to the Jewish Institute of Religion, January 1922
  - Derashah she-darash harav hagadol rabenu Mosheh bar Nahman ... me-erets Katalonia lifne ha-melekh veha-sarim ..., 1875 (Box 48, Folder 1708)
  - Traduksyon livre de 35 poezias ebraikas de Rosh ha-shana i Kippur, i selihoth, 1922 (Box 48, Folder 1709)
    Poems translated from the Hebrew. Ladino texts in Rashi script.
  - Mi-shire ha-zam, 1902 (Box 48, Folder 1710)
  - Aluf batslut ve-aluf shum: bedihah mamit be-haruzim, 1928 (Box 48, Folder 1711)
  - Lo dubim ve-lo yar o, Mishpat tsedek: le-hotsi et tsidkat ... Elizer Tsvaifel mi-divre H. Shatskes, 1890 (Box 48, Folder 1712)
    Library's copy imperfect; missing pages 49-56
  - Tenuah ha-tsiyonit veha-tokhniyot le-yishuv Aram-Naharayim ba- tekufah shele-ahar Hertsel, 1965 (Box 48, Folder 1713)
    Added t. p.: The Zionist movement and the schemes for the settlement of Mesopotamia after Herzl
  - Toldot ha-yamin she-vru l Hevra-Kadisha Shivh Kerim ve-l bet ha-midrash ha-gadol asher ba-r Minsk mi-shenat 523 d...664: vol. 1, 1904 (Box 48, Folder 1714)
  - Toldot ha-yamin she-vru l Hevra-Kadisha Shivh Kerim ve-l bet ha-midrash ha-gadol asher ba-r Minsk mi-shenat 523 d...664: vol. 2, 1911 - 1912 (Box 48, Folder 1715)
    Vol. 2 published in Minsk. Cover date of vol. 2 does not match date on title page.
  - Eyne kurtse bashraybung iber eynige historishe erter fun erets Yisroel un ihre zeltene deynkmeler, 1888 (Box 48, Folder 1716)
    Title and publication information also in Russian.
  - Sefer Yetsirah ha-meyuhas le-Avraham avinu = Sepher Yetzirah (The book of creation), 1895 (Box 48, Folder 1717)
  - Masekhet niyut min Talmud Rash lma, m perush Rashih ve-tos., nimtset ba-r gozel, r meleh niyim ve-evyonim ve-nisderet a. y. ha-kabtsan, rosh ha-dalfanim, rav ni ha-gadol; ve-nitosfu bah tosafot, hidushim ve-hagahot mi-hagaho zikne ha-batlanim ..., 1878 (Box 48, Folder 1718)
  - Auerbach family: the descendants of Abraham Auerbach, 1960 (Box 48, Folder 1719)
    Supplement 1
  - Auerbach family: the descendants of Abraham Auerbach, 1962 (Box 48, Folder 1720)
    Supplement 2
  - Auerbach family: the descendants of Abraham Auerbach:, 1965 (Box 48, Folder 1721)
    Supplement 3
  - Report of the Secretary and Special Delegate of the Joint Foreign Committee on questions of Jewish interest at the sixth assembly of the League, 1925 (Box 48, Folder 1722)
    At head of title: League of Nations, Geneva, 1925
  - Report of the Secretary and Special Delegate of the Joint Foreign Committee on questions of Jewish interest at the seventh assembly of The League, 1926 (Box 48, Folder 1723)
    At head of title: The League of Nations, Geneva, 1926
  - Introduction to Zionism and Israel, 1956 (Box 48, Folder 1724)
    Library's copy water damaged.
  - Guide to Zionism, 1948 (Box 48, Folder 1725)
    Special reprint for Intercollegiate Zionist Federation of America
  - Zion: incorperating the New Judaea, Vol. 1, no. 1, 08/1949 (Box 48, Folder 1726)
  - Zion: incorperating the New Judaea, Vol. 1, no. 5-6, 01/1950 (Box 48, Folder 1727)
  - Zion: incorperating the New Judaea, Vol. 2, no. 2, 02/1951 (Box 48, Folder 1728)
  - Liberty bell: vol. 6; no. 6, 2/1979 (Box 48, Folder 1729)
    Anti-Semitic pamphlet. Liberty Bell Publications: Reedy, West Virginia.
  - Patterns of prejudice: vo. 3, no. 2, 03/1969 (Box 48, Folder 1730)
  - Patterns of prejudice: vol. 1, no. 2, 03/1967 (Box 48, Folder 1731)
  - Jews in England and America in the 17th and 18th centuries, edited with glossary and notes, 1938 (Box 48, Folder 1732)
    Jdische Lesehefte; Heft 28
  - American impact: Judaism in the United States in the early nineteenth century, 1964 (Box 48, Folder 1733)
    B. G. Rudolph lectures in Judaic studies. Lecture delivered on April 29, 1964, at Syracuse University.
  - Jewish thought as a factor in civilization, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 1734)
    The Race question and modern thought
  - Voice of prophecy in this satellite age, 1959 (Box 48, Folder 1735)
    The Goldenson lecture; 1959
  - Mission of the Jewish people in history and in the modern world, 1964 (Box 48, Folder 1736)
    A lecture delivered at the Lutheran World Federation Consultation on the Church and the Jewish People, held at Logumkloster, Denmark, April 26-May 2, 1964
  - Jew and Christian, 1927 (Box 48, Folder 1737)
    Half title: Jew and Christian: a collection of addresses
  - Commentary to Union prayer book, vol. 1, newly revised: first evening service for the sabbath: experimental edition, 1962 (Box 48, Folder 1738)
  - Rediscovery of Judaism: a re-examination of the conciliar statement on the Jews, 1971 (Box 48, Folder 1739)
  - Blood test as proof of kinship in Jewish folklore, 1903 (Box 48, Folder 1740)
    Reprinted: Journal of the American Oriental Society. Vol. 24, First Half, 1903
  - Alfabeta de-Ven Sira: rishonah u-sheniyah: m ha-perush ha-yashan ha-kolel meshalim u-masiyot u-midrashot, 1858 (Box 48, Folder 1741)
    Title page also in Latin: Alphabetum Siracidis utrumque cum expositione antiqua (narrationes et fabulas continente). In integrum restitum ey emendatum e. Cod. MS. Biblioth. Leydensis a M. Steinschneider
  - Topics of to-day in the Talmud, 1889 (Box 48, Folder 1742)
    Library's copy signed by the author and dedicated to editor of the Light. Reprinted from the Jewish Standard.
  - Even mi-kir tizak, 1961 (Box 48, Folder 1743)
  - Midreshe ha-Zohar l Torah Nevim u-Khetuvim: le-fi seder ha-parashiyot veha-pesukim, 1933 (Box 48, Folder 1744)
    Added t.p.: Midrashe ha-Zohar, Midrashic selections from the Zohar
  - Tashlum penine ha-Zohar; kolel pitgamin, imre-nom, vikhuhim, ve-kol ha-meshalim me-sefer ha-Zohar, 1933 (Box 48, Folder 1745)
    Added t. p.: Additament [sic] to Penine ha-Zohar; containing saws, bon mots, controversies, and parables culled from the Zohar and annotated.
  - Sifra de-Agadta: Agadot ha-Zohar l pi rakhin, 1934 (Box 48, Folder 1746)
    Added t. p.: Siphra da-agadta: Aggadot ha-Zohar
  - Sefer Pokeah vrim, 1939 (Box 48, Folder 1747)
  - Kritische Untersuchung des Midrasch Kohelet Rabba: I. Theil. Quellen und Redactionszeit., 1892 (Box 48, Folder 1748)
  - Leben des Rabbi Mosche ben Maimon: aus seinen Briefen und anderen Quellen ausgewhlt und eingeleitet, 1935 (Box 48, Folder 1749)
    Jdische Lesehefte; Heft 5
  - Apologetik des Jdentums, 1892 (Box 48, Folder 1750)
  - Von der weltkulturellen Bedeutung und Aufgabe des Judentums, 1916 (Box 48, Folder 1751)
    Weltkultur und Weltpolitik; Deutsche und sterreichische Schriftenfolge; Deutsche folge. 8
  - Licht: Jahrgang 1 - Heft 1; "Juden in den Kriegs' Gesellschaften", 4/1920 (Box 48, Folder 1752)
    Each issue also has a distinctive title. Description based on: Heft 6 (1922).
  - Deutsche Vortrupp Febr./Mrz 1934, 2/1934 (Box 48, Folder 1753)
    "Bltter einer Gefolgschaft Deutscher Juden."
  - Zur jdisch-religisen Gegenwartslage, 1938 (Box 48, Folder 1754)
    Jdische Wirklichkeit heute; eine Schriftenreihe; Heft 1
  - Anti-Anti-Bltter zur Abwehr: Tatsachen zur Judenfrage, 1920 - 1929 (Box 48, Folder 1755)
    Collection of pamphlets arranged alphabetically by topic. Includes index.
  - Rechtswesen in Palaestina; eine Sammlung von Aufsaetzen aus dem Mitteilungsblatt der Hitachduth Olej Germania, 1935 (Box 48, Folder 1756)
  - Judentum und Christentum, 1919 (Box 48, Folder 1757)
    "Die erste Auflage erschien 1914 als Heft V des II. Jahrgangs der von Dr. J. Ziegler, Karlsbad, herausgegebenen 'Volksschriften ber die jdische Religion.'"
  - Entstehung des Schulchan-Aruch: Beitrag zur Festlegung der Halacha, 1915 (Box 48, Folder 1758)
    Chiefly in German with some Hebrew.
  - Eyner tsvishn milyonen: fun an Amerikaner nesie, 1930 (Box 48, Folder 1759)
    Library's copy lacks several pages
  - Sefer Kadish le-lam: ve-hu helek me-hiburi ... Ginat egoz ...: bur nakhon l ha-kadish ..., 1890 (Box 48, Folder 1760)
    Library's copy is missing the last page
  - Beliefs and practices of Judaism, 1941 (Box 48, Folder 1761)
  - Mizrah-Eyropeisher Yid, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 1762)
    Added t.p. in English: The East-European Jew
  - Shelah bed ha-hayim el ha-metim, 1915 (Box 49, Folder 1763)
    Mosessohn, N. (Nehemiah), 1853-1926. New York: Lipshitz Press, 1915. Responsa allowing autopsies on tuberculosis victims. Also see K0001/004-0053#02075, which consists of a Hebrew manuscript written by Moses Hayyim Rabinowitz, 1853-1934, discussing Mosessohn's book.
  - Konkordantsyah le-Sefer ha-razim: (ha-pol veha-shem), 1966 (Box 49, Folder 1764)
    At head of title: Universitat Tel Aviv
  - Aboda Zara: der Mishnatraktat "Gtzendienst", 1909 (Box 49, Folder 1765)
    2., neubearb. Aufl., mit deutscher bersetzung. Schriften des Institutum Judaicum in Berlin; Nr. 31
  - Frau im jdischen Volke: Vortrag gehalten am 21. Januar 1884 im Isr. Frauenwohlthtigkeits-Verein in Berlin, 1901 (Box 49, Folder 1766)
    Missing pages 25-32.
  - Sefer Dine vodah: osef halakhot u-minhagim be-yahase vdim u-mavidim, 1942 (Box 49, Folder 1767)
  - Talmudische Tractat Derech Erez Sutta nach Handschriften und seltenen Ausgaben: mit Parallelstellen und Varianten kritisch bearbeitet, bersetzt und erlutert, 1885 (Box 49, Folder 1768)
    Thesis (Inaugural-Dissertation)--Albertus-Universitt zu Knigsberg i Pr., 1885
  - Sefer Pirke Avot: ha-nemarim ba-Shabatot she-ben Pesah la-tseret ... Nidpesu me-hadash m laz Sefaradi be-hagahah mezukeket u-musheret., 1946 (Box 49, Folder 1769)
    Hebrew and Ladino
  - Yashav metsaref: kolel berur va-sefat dinim ha-nohagim ba-noladim me-vot tarovot Yehudi vese-no Yehudi, 1899 (Box 49, Folder 1770)
  - World Over, a magazine for youth, 01/29/1971 (Box 49, Folder 1771)
  - Pictorial oddities from Hebraic literature, 1967 (Box 49, Folder 1772)
  - Guide to Jewish Palestine, 1927 (Box 49, Folder 1773)
  - Guide to Jewish Palestine, 1930 (Box 49, Folder 1774)
    Later editions have title: Guide to new Palestine
  - Story of Jerusalem, 1950 (Box 49, Folder 1775)
  - Ancient Jerusalem, 1930 - 1940 (Box 49, Folder 1776)
    Published for the Zionist Organization Youth Dept. by E. Pikovsky
  - Proposal for an international curatorship for the holy places submitted to the United Nations, 1949 (Box 49, Folder 1777)
  - Jerusalem before the United Nations, 1950 (Box 49, Folder 1778)
  - Jerusalem by moonlight, and The Hebrew race: two excerpts from the writings of Benjamin Disraeli, 1965 (Box 49, Folder 1779)
    Sixty copies printed on various papers for private distribution
  - Jerusalem by moonlight, and The Hebrew race: two excerpts from the writings of Benjamin Disraeli, 1965 (Box 49, Folder 1780)
    This is a duplicate; sixty copies printed on various papers for private distribution
  - Description of a view of the city of Jerusalem: and the surrounding country, now exhibiting at the Panorama, Broadway ... New York painted by Robert Burford from drawings taken in 1834 by F. Catherwood, architect, 1838 (Box 49, Folder 1783)
    Printer's name and date appear on cover
  - Hagode fon hayntiger tsayt, oder, Hayntiger seyder, 1885 (Box 49, Folder 1784)
  - Jew in the American novel, 1959 (Box 49, Folder 1785)
    Herzl Institute pamphlet, no. 10
  - Rose Freeman-Ishill: reviews & comments with an unpublished letter by Havelock Ellis, 1951 (Box 49, Folder 1786)
    Portrait of author identified as woodcut by Maurice Duvalet
  - Seer in darkness; a group of three poems, 1964 (Box 49, Folder 1787)
    Handset in Bodoni book with 3 woodengravings by Dr. Alexander Anderson ... (printed from original blocks) 70 copies on Strathmore pastelle and 30 copies on Warren olde style, for private distribution
  - Mark Twain: racist?: the social attitudes of Samual Clemens, 1960 - 1970 (Box 49, Folder 1788)
    This selection is a brief summary of Chapter 6, 'The Brotherhood of Man', found in 'Mark Twain: social critic,' by Philip S. Froner
  - Avi David Yelin: devarim le-zikhro li-melot meah shanah le-huladeto, 1964 (Box 49, Folder 1789)
    Ba-mesibah he-hodshit ha-meah sheloshim ve-ahat shel Berit Ivrit olamit, Yerushalayim, 12 be-Adar, 724
  - Lehr-bikhel fun D.A.R. far Birgershaft, 1940 (Box 49, Folder 1790)
    Translated from the 17th English edition
  - Leo Baeck, the man and the idea, 1958 (Box 49, Folder 1791)
    The Leo Baeck memorial lecture; 1
  - Juden in Freiburg i. B., 1890 (Box 49, Folder 1792)
  - Geschichte der Juden in Strassburg: von der zeit Karls d. Gr. bis auf die gegenwart, 1894 (Box 49, Folder 1793)
  - Religion in Geschichte und Gegenwart; Handwrterbuch fr Theologie und Religionswissenschaft, 1931 (Box 49, Folder 1794)
    Bd. 5: Bogen 39; pg.1218-1247
  - Oyf vos bedarfen Yuden a land?: etlekhe erenste verter farn folk, 1898 (Box 49, Folder 1795)
  - Kongres-reden, 1918 (Box 49, Folder 1796)
    fun Daytshen original iberzetst durkh S. Abel
  - Folk un land: zamlbikher spetsyel gevidmete der filozofish-gezelshaftlikher oyfklerung ..., 1910 (Box 49, Folder 1797)
  - Hagadah shel Pesah, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 1798)
    Haggadah. Kibbuts version. 1947
  - Talmudstudium in der ersten Hlfte dez neunzehnten Jahrhunderts in den Jeschibot zu Nikolsburg, Posen und Pressburg, 1901 (Box 49, Folder 1799)
  - I.O.B.B. (Independent Order of B'nai B'rith), 1905 (Box 49, Folder 1800)
    Ed. rev. by order of the General Convention of 1905
  - Nuovi manoscritti ebraici della R. Biblioteca Nazionale di Firenze: secondo articolo, 1910 (Box 49, Folder 1801)
    Estratto dal Giornale della Societa Asiatica Italiana, vol. 22, anno 1909
  - Nuovi manoscritti ebraici della R. Biblioteca Nazionale di Firenze: secondo articolo, 1908 (Box 49, Folder 1802)
    Estratto dal Giornale della Societa Asiatica Italiana, vol. 21, anno 1908
  - Our debt to tradition: an address to the annual congress of the Society of Colonial Wars held on 23rd May 1964 at Cincinnati, Ohio, and attended by delegates from twenty states (Box 49, Folder 1803)
    Bibliography: page 16.
  - Sifra de-agadta, agadot ha-Zohar l pi rkhin nilketu venisderu m harot, 1934 (Box 49, Folder 1804)
    Added title page in English
  - Solomon Maimon's doctrine of infinite reason and its historical relations, 1953 (Box 49, Folder 1805)
    Reprinted from Journal of the History of Ideas Vol. XIII, no. 2 April 1952
  - Verzeichniss der Judaica aus der Bibliothek des Herrn Dr. H.B. Levy in Hamburg = Mikdash met: reshimat sifre defus u-kitve yad asher assaf u-kabets ha-adon ...Hayyim ... Ha-Levi, 1900 (Box 49, Folder 1806)
    Library catalogued by Salomon Goldschmidt, grandson of H.B. Levy
  - Hebrisches Wrterbuch zu Jesaja, 1936 (Box 49, Folder 1807)
    Einzelwrterbcher zum Alten Testament; Heft 2
  - Hebrew manuscripts in the Houghton Library of the Harvard College Library, 1975 (Box 49, Folder 1808)
    a catalogue prepared by Mordechai Glatzer; edited by Charles Berlin and Rodney Gove Dennis
  - Katalog der Hebraica und Judaica aus der Bibliothek von David Kulp, 1933 (Box 49, Folder 1809)
  - Books for Brotherhood, 1959 - 1960 (Box 49, Folder 1810)
    A booklist for adults, young people and children
  - Lantern, 07/1956 - 09/1956 (Box 49, Folder 1811)
    In English and Afrikaans. Lantern: vol. 6, no. 1
  - Mahberet: no.1-3 (54-56) Nov. 1956, 11/1956 (Box 49, Folder 1826)
    Cahiers de l'Alliance israelite universelle. In Hebrew and French.
  - American Fund news: Vol. 4, no. 4: Dec. 1948, 12/1948 (Box 49, Folder 1827)
  - Freiburger Stadthefte: No. 6; 1963 "Geschichte und Schicksal der Freiburger Juden" (Box 49, Folder 1828)
    Herausgegeben von der Stadtischen Pressestelle in Verbindung mit dem Verlag Rombach
  - Sefer Be-reshit (romanized form) = Liber Genesis, 1969 (Box 49, Folder 1829)
    Biblia Hebraica Stuttgartensia, v 1
  - Saadia Al-fajjmi's arabische Psalmenbersetzung und Commentar. (Psalm 21-41.) Nach einer Mnchener und einer Berliner Handschrift, 1901 (Box 49, Folder 1830)
    Text in Judeo-Arabic and German. Added t. p. in Judeo-Arabic.Bibliographical footnotes.
  - Pentateuch, its languages and its characters. A treatise upon the original language and the early translations of the Pentateuch into Greek and Aramaic, 1894 (Box 49, Folder 1831)
    "A chapter of my forthcoming book: What is the Talmud?": p. 31-38.
  - Pattern of Scripture, 1959 (Box 49, Folder 1832)
    Canterbury books
  - Society of Biblical Literature ... annual meeting paper titles, abstracts, annual reports, 1970 (Box 49, Folder 1833)
    Abstracts: Society of Biblical Literature ... annual meeting
  - Novi, 1929 (Box 49, Folder 1834)
    On verso of t.p.: The prophet; translated into Yiddish with the permission of the author by Isaac Horowitz
  - Davka, 03/1972 - 04/1972 (Box 49, Folder 1835)
    vol. 2, no. 3
  - Davka, 05/1972 - 06/1972 (Box 49, Folder 1836)
  - TaNaKH un Arkheologia, 1950 (Box 49, Folder 1837)
    Separater Opdruk fun Yivo Bleter, bd. 34. Inscribed "Far meyn freynd un kolege Prof. Kiev, a matunah funem mahaver.
  - Simon Bernstein, scholar, author, editor, 1949 (Box 49, Folder 1838)
  - Don Jizchak Abravanel, 1937 (Box 49, Folder 1839)
    Includes bibliographical references
  - Americanization of Isaac Mayer Wise, 1931 (Box 49, Folder 1840)
  - Gedenkreden beim Heimgang des Altrabbiners Prof. Dr. Sigmund Salfeld, Mainz, 1926 (Box 49, Folder 1841)
    Cover title: Zum Andenken an Prof. Dr. Sigmund Salfeld
  - ltesten Daten Israels und die durch Berechnung gefundenen genauen Daten der Richterzeit, 1934 (Box 49, Folder 1842)
  - Midrash Eleh ezkerah: nyano maseh seret haruge malkhut, 1853 (Box 49, Folder 1843)
    Martyrology of ten famous rabbis
  - Wisdom for modern man: Proverbs and Ecclesiastes from the Old Testament, in today's English version, 1974 (Box 49, Folder 1844)
  - Samuel and the beginnings of the prophetic movement, 1961 (Box 49, Folder 1845)
    The Goldenson lecture, 1961
  - Prophetenideal Judentum und Christentum: das Hauptproblem der sptisraelitischen Religionsgeschichte, 1906 (Box 49, Folder 1846)
    Includes bibliographical references.
  - Naye shtimme, 05/1904 (Box 49, Folder 1847)
    Die Neue Stimme (the New Voice) a radical-Zionistic Periodical. Vol. 1, no. 1
  - Zionist activity on the campus, 1947 (Box 49, Folder 1848)
  - Report for period ... for period April 1954 - May 1955 =Din ve-heshbon l ha-pelot, 1954 - 1955 (Box 49, Folder 1849)
    In English and Hebrew, with title also in Hebrew.